新疆维吾尔自治区新疆生产建设兵团二零二五年初中学业水平考试英语试卷听力部分。请大家做好准备，听力测试现在开始。
a 1. Greece went to Beijing by train yesterday
图片理解：根据听到的句子内容，选择正确的图片。每小题读两遍。
2. There will be a volleyball match on Saturday
3. Tim plays the guitar at 8 o every evening
4. Many children like to eat ice cream in summer
5. The blue jacket fits you very well
b 6. May I speak to Helen, please?
情景反应，听句子，选择正确的应答。每小题读两遍。
7. Have a nice trip in Xinjiang
8. How often do you go to the movies?
9. I think classic music is relaxing
10. Let's volunteer in the old people's home
c 11. Jack, would you please take out the rubbish?
对话理解：听对话及问题，选择正确的答案。每组对话读两遍。
11. Jack, would you please take out the rubbish?
12. Mike, what is your dream job?
My parents expect me to be a doctor, but I prefer to be a basketball player
What is Mike's dream job?
It's still raining heavily outside
17. That's too bad, we have to put off our picnic to next Sunday
When will they have their picnic?
What is notebooks are nice?
Whose are they?
21. What color is Judy's notebook?
Whose notebooks are nice?
are they? is mine, and the red one is my sister Judy's 24.
What color is Judy's notebook?
25. Here is your order, sir,
what else would you like?
That's enough for dinner 27.
Where are the two speakers?
Where are the speakers?
Where two speakers?
短文理解：听短文，选择正确的答案。短文读两遍。
There are three kites on the boat 31.
Do you think they are there just for fun?
32. No, they are working with their owner Henry
33. Henry is a fisherman,
and he is 71 years old 34.
He lives near a river
35. Most mornings before he pushes his small boat into the river to go fishing
36. He will bring his three kites into the boat
37. They are good helpers for Henry 38.
When the cats stand straight,
Henry knows there are fish to catch
39. When Henry gets fish,
he shares some fish with the cats 40.
Every cat on the boat gets excited 41.
course, Henry has to watch the cats 42.
to make sure they won't eat all the fish
43. Look, there are three cats on the boat
44. Do you think they are there just for fun?
45. they are working with their owner Henry 46.
Henry is a fisherman, and he is 71 years old 47.
He lives near a river 48.
Most mornings before he pushes his small boat into the river to go fishing 49.
He will bring his three cats into the boat 50.
They are good helpers for Henry 50.
When the cats stand straight,
Henry knows there are fish to catch 51.
When Henry gets fish,
he shares some fish with the cats
Every cat on the boat gets excited 53.
Of course, Henry has to watch the cats 54.
to make sure they won't eat all the fish
55. is
听力测试到此结束。